Andrew McMechan

UI/UX Designer

Hey, I'm Andrew! I'm a Software Engineer turned UI/UX Designer based in Bonn, Germany. Born and raised in Belfast, Ireland, I moved to Bonn, Germany in 2016 to expand my career opportunties on the continent. My current focus is User Experience Design for a number of customer facing products with the Deutsche Telekom.

EXPERIENCE

cronn GmbH / UI/UX Designer

SEPTEMBER 2017 - PRESENT

Having been involved since the PoC Phase of my current project, I have gained a lot of experience in transitioning from a lone designer in a team of 8 people, to a SAFe project with over 10 designers and around 150 collaborators.

cronn GmbH / Software Developer

JUNE 2016 - AUGUST 2017

Using the GWT Framework, I was part of a team responsible for a Web Interface used by the various regional branches of the Deutsche Telekom for the administration of provisioned SIM cards. My main responsibilities and duties revolved around Java, JUnit, Mockito, SOAP API and Selenium testing.

Liberty IT / Associate Software Engineer

SEPTEMBER 2015 - MAY 2016

Worked with the Usability Team for Commercial Insurance Software to ensure a good experience for Insurance Agenta across America. Main responsibilites were Java, Struts, JQuery and JUnit

EDUCATION

University of Ulster / MSc Software Development SEPTEMBER 2014

DEV

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Git, Webpack, React, Jawa, JUnit, GWT

DESIGN

Sketch, Rapid-Prototyping, Invision, Illustrator, Photoshop

OTHER

Accessibility, SCRUM, Agile, SAFe, JIRA,

CERTIFICATIONS

- Accessibility: How to design for all (www.idf.org)
- Design thinking (www.idf.org)
- User Experience Design (www.coursera.com)
- Deutsch B2
 (Queen's University Belfast)
- Deutsch B1
 (Goethe Institute Dublin)
- Oracle Certified Java Associate